Hey, hey, what's up? My friend. So, have
a look at this
chart over here. This is an equity curve
of a trading system.
And over here you have three points.
Point A, B, and C. A,
B, and C.
Now, let me ask you.
When is the best time to start trading
this system? At point A, point B, or
point C? I'll give you 5 seconds. 1 2 3
4 5. Okay. So, before I give you the
answer, let me explain to you my take on
it. All right, so at point A,
okay, at point A,
this is when the trading system is on
fire because you see that the equity
curve, the results of this system,
right, has been making consistent money
over the last few years. Traders are
balling, you know, posting pictures of
their rented Lambos and creating their
own courses. Huh. That's at point A.
However, if market conditions change,
and you bet it will, this trading system
will go into a drawdown, and those
latecomers will have to embrace the full
decline, the full impact of the
drawdown. So, that's what's happening at
point A. Now, what about point B, which
is here?
Okay. So, at point B, the trading system
is already in a drawdown, meaning it's
really losing money, having having
experienced some losses.
Traders are losing money, but if you
have a trading system that works,
that has a proven edge in the market,
the drawdown will eventually end.
And your equity curve will eventually,
you know, break out to new all-time
high. As you can see over here, you
break out to new all-time high once
again.
Oh, how about point C? If you look at
this point C,
this is the best part, point C, because
the trading system is in a sustained
drawdown. If you enter at C, this is
where, shortly afterwards, you can
experience
a series of winning trades and start
making money almost immediately at point
C. So,
so here's the thing, right?
You never know with certainty, right,
whether a trading system is going to be
trading right now at A
or C. A meaning you never know for sure
if a trading system is just about to
enter a drawdown at this point. It's
anyone's guess. At the same time, you
also know you never know for sure when a
system is about to recover and break out
to new equity highs. You following me?
So, if you ask me, the best time to
trade a system is when it's in a
drawdown, you want to give it a shot.
So, anywhere between point B and point
C, those are, you know, good times to
start trading the system. And the reason
is simple. It's when you trade a new
system when it's going through a
drawdown, you get to escape the full
length of a drawdown. Right, that's
because you don't have to experience
if, let's say, someone at A who started
here, they have to experience this
entire full length of this decline of
this drawdown. Whereas someone who,
let's say, entered somewhere between B
and C where the drawdown has already
partially occurred, let's say you enter
somewhere here, you can see that your
decline that you have to experience is
shorter. So, anywhere between point B
and C, you would escape the full length
of the drawdown.
And your account will reach a new equity
high faster. So, let me give you an
example, right, so you understand what
this means. So, let's say, for example,
John, right, bought Microsoft stock for
$100. Then the price declined to 70
bucks.
Okay, so that's, you can see over here,
for John, it's a 30% drawdown because
you buy something at $100, it declines
to $70, it's a 30% drawdown. And let's
say, just for this example's sake, at
this point, Sally bought the stocks at
$70 because it was on sale. And then the
stock price continued to a low of $50.
So, from 70 down to 50, that is a
drawdown of about, you know,
20% thereabout. Yeah, lesser than the
drawdown that John has experienced.
And 1 year later, let's say the stock
price rallied back to $100.
So, what's the result for both John and
Sally? So, you can see over here,
because John
bought it at $100, and 1 year later the
stock price is $100, John is at break
even, right, BE. For Sally, she bought
it at $70, and now it went back to $100,
that's a gain of about $30 per share,
per stock.
So, and that's about a 42% gain for
Sally.
So, as you can see, right, John has
endured the full length and depth of the
drawdown for from $100
down to $70. Sorry, I mean, actually
down to $50 for John.
Okay?
And when the price recovered, he was
still at break even.
At the same time, for Sally, she
actually entered during a drawdown. So,
you can see over here, Sally entered
during a drawdown at $70, and she earned
a higher return and experienced a
shorter duration of the drawdown as
well.
So, can you see the difference between
John and Sally when someone is
trading when a system is in a drawdown
compared to someone who, let's say, is
unlucky, who's chasing the system,
right, when it's performing well, and
then having to endure the full brunt of
the drawdown?
Now, the reason I'm sharing this example
with you is because the concept applies
to systems trading.
If you start trading a new system when
it's in a drawdown, you will earn a
higher return compared to someone who
who entered at the peak of the trading
system's performance. All right, and
what happens is that you'll experience a
a shorter duration of the drawdown,
you'll experience a shorter depth of the
drawdown. So,
if you're looking to, you know, trade a
new system, right, if you ask me, this
is a good time. And by the way, if you
want to learn proven trading systems
that work, maybe you don't have a
trading system that you can reliably
trust or use, then you can actually grab
my free training over here at
tradingwithrayner.com/
go. I'll put the link somewhere below
this video, so you can
get this free training where you will
learn three proven trading systems that
work, backed by 25 years of data. So,
the trading rules, they are
quantifiable, they are in black and
white, no subjectivity and whatnot. So,
I'll put the link somewhere below this
video, so you can grab a copy of this
training to learn these three different
trading systems. For example, one of
them is a mean reversion system, up
about 2,800% over the last 25 years, and
much more. So, if you're interested,
I'll put the link below, download, grab
a copy, and I'll talk to you soon.